Welcome back to Jupyter Lab and welcome to Day Five's Lab.
Jupyter Labへようこそ､ そして5日目のラボへようこそ｡
And this is going to be lots of creativity and hopefully lots of entertainment.
そして､ これはたくさんの創造性と､ できればたくさんのエンターテインメントになるだろう｡
So to start with I have copied the day four Jupyter Lab.
そこでまず､ 4日目のJupyter Labをコピーしてみた｡
And I've duplicated that.
そして､ 私はそれを再現した｡
And then I've extended it.
そして､ それを延長したんだ｡
So everything above where I am now is just a repeat of day four.
だから､ 今いるところより上は､ すべて4日目の繰り返しなんだ｡
Creates the AI assistant for our airline called flight flight AI, something like that, and arms it
フライトAIと呼ばれる航空会社のAIアシスタントを作成し､ 航空券の価格を知ることができるツールを持たせる｡
All of that is already there and I've executed it ready for our showtime today.
そのすべてがすでにあり､ 今日のショータイムのために準備してきた｡
We're going to go multi-modal.
私たちはマルチモーダルを目指す｡
We're going to use Dall-E three, which is the image generation model that sits behind GPT four.
私たちは､ GPT 4の後ろに位置するイメージ生成モデルであるDall-E 3を使うつもりです｡
We're going to use it to make some images.
これを使って画像を作るんだ｡
And let's start by putting it into a function called artist.
そして､ それをartistという関数に入れることから始めよう｡
Before that, there are two, uh, service announcements I should make.
その前に､ 2つ､ ええと､ サービスアナウンスがあるんだ｡
Uh, first of all, I should point out that the price associated with generating an image is not tiny.
ええと､ まず最初に言っておかなければならないのは､ 画像生成にかかる料金は決して小さなものではないということだ｡
Everything that we've done so far, I hope, has had a de minimis price in the fractions of a cent.
私たちがこれまでやってきたことはすべて､ 1セントの何分の1という最小限の価格だったと思う｡
Unless you've been generating tons of lengthy brochures, you have not racked up a significant bill
長大なパンフレットを大量に作成しているのでなければ､ このコースの運営で多額の請求が来ることはないだろう｡
But now we are doing something that's slightly more on the radar.
でも､ 今はもう少しレーダーに近いことをやっている｡
Each image that we generate will cost $0.04.
弊社が生成する各画像は0ドルです｡  04.
Now, I put it to you that when you see these images, you will agree that they are well worth $0.04
さて､ これらの画像をご覧になれば､ 0ドルの価値は十分にあるとご納得いただけるだろう｡  各04ドル｡
And they are super creative and high value.
しかも､ 超クリエイティブで価値が高い｡
And I love them.
私は彼らを愛している｡
So I think it is money well spent.
だから､ 私は十分なお金を使ったと思う｡
But I do want to inform you of that so that you can decide whether you want to spend your $0.04 each
でも､ 0ドルを使うかどうかを決めるために､ そのことはお知らせしておきたい｡  毎回04｡
Uh, the other thing to mention is that there is a little bit of, uh, um, uh, there's there's a
もうひとつ言っておくと､ 画像生成や音声生成などにLMという言葉を使うべきかどうかという点で､ 少し､ あー､ あー､ あー､
there's a point about whether or not one should use the term LM when referring to image generation and
あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､ あー､
audio generation and the like.
あー､ あー､ あー､ あー｡
Text to audio.
テキストから音声へ｡
Because of course, these are not large language models sitting behind the scenes.
というのも､ もちろん､ これらは舞台裏にある大規模な言語モデルではないからだ｡
Now, what tends to happen these days is that people use LM as a bit of a general term for the models
さて､ 最近起こりがちなのは､ 人々はLMを､ 一般的なAIシステムの背後にあるモデルの総称として使っているということだ｡
So actually, in practice, I think this very much is part of the skill set and toolkit of an LM engineer.
だから実際には､ これはLMエンジニアのスキルセットとツールキットの一部だと思う｡
But I should mention that, of course, strictly speaking, these aren't language models.
しかし､ もちろん､ 厳密に言えば､ これらは言語モデルではないということは言っておかなければならない｡
These are image models and audio models that we'll be playing with right now as we add them to our agent
これらは画像モデルとオーディオモデルで､ これからエージェントフレームワークに追加して遊ぶことになる｡
Anyways, with that preamble, let's get on with it.
ともあれ､ 前置きはこれくらいにして､ さっそく本題に入ろう｡
So we start by importing some useful image libraries.
そこで､ 便利な画像ライブラリをいくつかインポートすることから始めよう｡
Well, the first one isn't.
まあ､ 最初のは違うけどね｡
First two aren't image libraries, but some, some, uh, utilities.
最初の2つはイメージライブラリではなく､ いくつかのユーティリティだ｡
And then the Python image library is going to be very useful for us, a very handy common library.
そして､ Pythonのイメージ・ライブラリーは､ 私たちにとって非常に便利な共通ライブラリーです｡
Uh, so the next thing we do is we're going to write a function called artist and artist calls OpenAI
次にやることは､ artistという関数を書いて､ artistがOpenAI dot images dot generateを呼び出すことだ｡
So it's a very consistent style that you're used to OpenAI images generate.
つまり､ OpenAIの画像が生成するのに慣れた､ 非常に一貫したスタイルなのだ｡
We pass in the name of a model.
モデル名でパスを出す｡
In this case, the model is Dall-E three.
この場合､ モデルはDall-E 3である｡
You could also try Dall-E two, its predecessor.
その前身である『Dall-E two』を試してみるのもいいだろう｡
The images are less awesome.
画像はそれほど素晴らしいものではない｡
It's a bit cheaper.
もう少し安い｡
I seem to remember it's about $0.02 rather than $0.04, so it's not massively cheaper and in my opinion
0ドルくらいだったと記憶している｡  0ドルではなく02ドル｡  04なので､ 大幅に安いわけではなく､ 0ドル余分に払う価値は十分にあると私は思う｡
Stick with Dall-E three.
02.
We give it a prompt and this isn't now a clever list of dictionaries.
私たちはプロンプトを与え､ これは今､ 辞書の巧妙なリストではない｡
It's just text.
ただのテキストだ｡
And in this case, the prompt I'm suggesting here is, we say, an image representing a vacation in
この場合､ 私が提案するプロンプトは､ 例えば､ 都市での休暇を表現するイメージで､ 観光スポットや都市に関するあらゆるユニークなものを､
city, showing tourist spots and everything unique about city in a vibrant pop art style.
活気に満ちたポップアート・スタイルで表現するものだ｡
We give it a size that is the smallest size.
最小のサイズを与える｡
Dall-E three will do, Dall-E two will go much smaller.
Dall-E 3なら大丈夫､ Dall-E 2ならもっと小さくなる｡
Um and Dall-E three also does two larger sizes in a portrait and landscape format.
UmとDall-E threeは､ 縦型と横型の2つの大きなサイズも用意している｡
Just google it if you'd like to know those dimensions.
その寸法を知りたければググればいい｡
If you'd like to try those images.
もしこれらの画像を試してみたいなら｡
We just want one image back.
私たちはただ1枚の画像を返してほしいだけなのだ｡
We say we want this format.
私たちはこの形式を望んでいると言っている｡
Back comes something in the, uh, this um, uh, base64 encoded format.
Base64でエンコードされたフォーマットで戻ってくる｡
We then decode that into bytes, and then we then create a bytes IO object on those bytes, which we
そして､ それをバイトにデコードし､ そのバイトでバイトIOオブジェクトを作り､
can then pass in to the image dot open function, and that will return an image for us.
それをimage dot open関数に渡すと､ 画像を返してくれる｡
Let's execute that.
それを実行しよう｡
And now let's give it a try.
そして今､ それを試してみよう｡
So I'm going to say image equals artist.
だから､ 私はイメージ＝アーティストと言うつもりだ｡
And what shall we say New York City.
そしてニューヨーク・シティ｡
And then display image is the Jupiter way of then getting that to show.
そして､ 画像を表示させるのがジュピター流だ｡
Let's run that or you're seeing one I ran already there.
それを実行しましょう､ あるいは私がすでに実行したものがそこにあります｡
Sorry it's not that quick, but look how amazing that is.
そんなに早くないのは残念だけど､ 見てよ､ この素晴らしさを｡
Uh, you're already getting.
ええと､ もうわかっていますよね｡
I'm spoiling you by showing you one right away.
さっそく1つお見せしましょう｡
This is what it looks like.
こんな感じだ｡
It's generating a second one above you get to see the Statue of Liberty, a few different Empire State
自由の女神､ 数種類のエンパイアステートビル､ 空に浮かぶ飛行機､
buildings, some planes in the sky, and then a sort of image to Times Square with lots of signs and
そしてたくさんの看板とニューヨークのタクシーが綴られたタイムズスクエアのイメージのようなものを見ることができる｡
Look at that.
あれを見ろ｡
A yellow New York taxi.
黄色いニューヨークのタクシー｡
And Coca-Cola.
そしてコカ・コーラ｡
And a hot dog.
それとホットドッグ｡
A very New York iconic thing.
まさにニューヨークを象徴するものだ｡
Fantastic.
ファンタスティックだ｡
Meanwhile, it's built another image for us here.
その一方で､ ここでまた新たなイメージを構築してくれた｡
And.
そして
Wow, look at this one.
うわあ､ これを見てよ｡
It's different.
違うんだ｡
It's great.
素晴らしいよ｡
It's got a big jet over here.
こっちには大きなジェット機がある｡
It's got the Empire State Building, of course, multiple Empire State buildings, Statue of Liberty's.
エンパイア・ステート・ビルはもちろん､ 複数のエンパイア・ステート・ビルや自由の女神像がある｡
And it's got again the sort of thriving shops and taxi in the foreground like that, an iconic New York
ニューヨークを象徴するタクシーとホットドッグ｡
Uh, so the thing to mention is that these images, they're so creative and they're so different, we've
この画像はとてもクリエイティブで､ それぞれ違っていて､
got two now that we can see the one I did a moment ago and this one here, uh, and you can see how
さっきの画像とこの画像の2つをご覧ください｡
All right.
分かった｡
Well, I hope that you were entertained by that.
まあ､ 楽しんでもらえたなら幸いだ｡
And by all means, can I suggest spend some $0.04, generate a few images for yourself.
そして､ ぜひとも0ドルを使うことを提案してもいいかな｡  04､ 自分用にいくつかの画像を作成する｡
They're great.
彼らは素晴らしい｡
All right, let's add one more function.
よし､ もうひとつ機能を追加しよう｡
We're going to make a function that uses OpenAI's speech to generate some audio.
OpenAIの音声を使って音声を生成する関数を作ります｡
So we're going to use a couple of utility stuff here with a library called Pi Dub.
ここでは､ Pi Dubと呼ばれるライブラリを使って､ いくつかのユーティリティを使うことにしよう｡
That's very useful.
とても役に立つよ｡
We're going to write a function called talker.
これからtalkerという関数を書きます｡
And talker is going to call OpenAI dot audio dot speech dot create.
トーカーはOpenAI dot audio dot speech dot createを呼び出す｡
So if we look back up the image generation was OpenAI images generate.
つまり､ 画像生成はOpenAIの画像生成だったのだ｡
And for audio it's a case of uh OpenAI audio dot speech dot create.
オーディオについては､ OpenAIのオーディオ・ドット・スピーチ・ドット・クリエイトのケースだ｡
We pass in a model.
モデルを渡す｡
Um, and this is the model we're using, TTS one TTS stands for text to speech and is, uh, the, the
TTSはテキスト・トゥ・スピーチ（text to speech）の略で､
this kind of model that we're going for, we supply a voice.
音声を供給するモデルです｡
In this case we're going to try the voice.
今回は声を試してみよう｡
Onyx.
オニキス
There's something like eight different voices to try again.
8種類の声をもう一度試すことができるんだ｡
You can you can Google to see what they are.
それが何かはググればわかる｡
And we pass in the thing that this function was called.
そして､ この関数が呼ばれたことを渡す｡
With what comes back, we again create a bytes IO object to represent those bytes.
戻ってきたバイトで､ それらのバイトを表すbytes IOオブジェクトを再び作成する｡
And then we use this to this audio segment, uh creating it from a file and the audio stream and get
そして､ このオーディオ・セグメントを使って､ ファイルとオーディオ・ストリームからオーディオ・セグメントを作成し､ そのオーディオを再生する｡
So let's create that function and then let's say talker.
では､ その関数を作ってトーカーとしよう｡
Well hi there.
やあ､ こんにちは｡
There we go.
これでよし｡
As simple as that.
簡単なことだ｡
Uh, let's see how another voice sounds.
ええと､ 別の声がどう聞こえるか見てみよう｡
Let's see how alloy sounds.
合金の音を聞いてみよう｡
Let's put alloy in there.
そこに合金を入れよう｡
Well hi there.
やあ､ こんにちは｡
And that was alloy.
それが合金だった｡
I think we'll stick with onyx.
オニキスにこだわると思う｡
But you can try either.
しかし､ どちらでも試すことができる｡
And you can also put in some more there that you can experiment with and pick your favorite.
そして､ そこにさらにいくつか入れて､ 試してみて好きなものを選ぶこともできる｡
All right.
分かった｡
Well that's what we'll go with.
まあ､ それで行こう｡
Uh and now let's talk about the agent framework.
さて､ 次はエージェントのフレームワークについて話そう｡
I think we will break for the next video.
次のビデオまで休憩しよう｡
And that's where we'll take on our full agent framework.
そして､ そこで私たちは完全なエージェントの枠組みを手に入れることになる｡
See you then.
ではまた